Guide to the Marilyn J. Boxer Papers SC1212
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marilyn J. Boxer Papers
1867-2005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Boxer, Marilyn J.
SC1212
33.75 Linear Feet (24 boxes)
Access to Collection
Student work is restricted for 75 years from date of creation. Otherwise the materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes research notes and files on Women’s history, feminism, the history of Women’s Studies, and European socialist feminism in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Also included are correspondence files, curriculum files, and some of Boxer’s drafts.
Biographical / Historical
Marilyn J. Boxer is Professor of History Emerita at San Francisco State University. Boxer earned an AB in History from University of Redlands in 1965, and an MA (1966) and Ph.D. (1975) in History from University of California, Riverside. Prior to joining faculty at SFSU, Boxer lectured at Stanford from 2001-2002. She was also an affiliated scholar at the Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research at Stanford University from 1998-2002. Boxer’s research interests include Women’s history, and the history of Women’s Studies as a discipline.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2014-2018.
Women -- Europe -- History; Women's studies -- United States -- History.; Women and socialism; Boxer, Marilyn J.; Boxer, Marilyn J.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-124
  Scope and Contents note
  Box 1: SDSU women's studies, including reports. Box 2: early women's studies at SDSU; talks; documents and notes for WWA, chs 1 & 2; correspondence with SDSU. Box 3: dissertation printouts; corrsepondence and other materials for WWA & CS. Box 4: Source material for WWA; conference papers. Box 5: Notes, photocopies, drafts for WWA, chs 3-7. Box 6: women's studies in Europe; survey of women's studies students at SDSU, 2000. Box 7: NWSA conference material; publications; administrative records. Box 8: women's studies addresses; WWK ch. 8-9; WFN.
  - Report on the West Coast Women's Studies Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Feminist Revolution: Redstockings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Women's Studies Program Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Women's Studies Program Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Women's Studies Program Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Women's Studies Program Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Women's Studies Program Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Self Study prepared for an Academic Review of The Deparment of Women's Studies Fall 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Civil Rights Digest, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Toward a Feminist Transformation of the Academy, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Frontier A Journal of Women Studies Fall 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Women Studies Everywhere Winter 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Women Studies Newsletter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Women Studies At 25, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Basch Lecture, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Santa Cruz, 1982 Apr (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - What + Women Studies? New Views, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - San Diego State Official Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - San Diego State University Women's Studies Program, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Women Studies Program 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A Passion for History, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Women's Studies and Socialist Feminism, 1974 Apr. 20 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Saturday Review: The New Feminism, 1970 Feb. 21 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Saturday Review: No More Sugar and Spice, 1971 Oct. 16 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Women's Studies Program Three Years of Stuggle, 1973 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - San Diego State University Magazine: Women Studies at 25, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Women Studies Program 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - What is Women Studies?, 1974 Oct (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Articles: Women Studies, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - San Diego State Universtiy, 1990 Feb. 7 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - San Diego State University Presentation Boxers, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Advocacy, Inquiry, Experience: Building Women's Studies Together, 1995 Nov. 4 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Women Studies at 25 San Diego State Univeristy, Nov. 4 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Women Studies Bibliography: Seventy Essential Readings, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - San Diego State University 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women Studies at 30: San Francisco State Univeristy, 1991 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Women Studies at 40: San Deigo State University, 2009 Aug-Sept (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Women Studies Enrollment Data, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Women Studies History, 1971-1995 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Crypt Trip, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Represnting Women/Disciplining Feminism: Activism, Professionalism, and Women's Studies, 1998 Dec (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - My Two Essays + Women Studies Program, 1982-2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Introduction Speaking of Women Studies, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Women Studies Programs & Letters of Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Female Studies III, 1971 Dec (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Female Studies IV: Teaching About Women, 1971 Dec (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Shelia Tobias, 1994 Oct 6 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - What is Women Studies in the United States?, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Debate 2, 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Defining Women Studies, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Women Studies: General Education, 2001 May (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Letters of Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Women Studies Chain Letters of Correspondence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Students- Whar Are They? & Number of Majors, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Tenure Lines, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Letters of Correspondents, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Women Studies Governance, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Letters of Correspondence Jo Freeman, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Journals & Letters of Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Various Newsletters and Articles, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Community Colleges, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Scope Institution, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Conference, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Data Summary, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Women Studies On-line, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Graduate PhD Proposal, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - New Women Studies, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Trade Union Women's Studies, 1973 Oct 1 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Union W.A.G.E.: Breaking the Banks, 1975 Feb (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Memoirs by Carol Rowell Council, 2002 May (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Women Studies Disseartation Abstracts and Brief Citations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Page Proof Errors List, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Post-Copy: When Women Ask The Questions, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Copyediting Instructions, 1991 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Letters of Correspondence: When Women Ask the Questions, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Post-it Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Table of Contents, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Interviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Illustrations, 1991 Feb. 16 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - John Hopkins Correspondence with Press, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Prospectus Women Studies & Enclosed Materials, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - John Hopkins - Other Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - When Women Ask The Questions Correspondence, 1998 Apr. 16 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - To Do: Book, Library Research, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Interlibrary Loan/Book Purcahse Info, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence Kate, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Expenses, When Women Ask The Questions, 1997 Oct. 31 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Preface, 1997 Jan. 30 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Copyediting, 1997 Sept.-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Citing Email, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sister Newsletter, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Copyright Assignment, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence w/ Oxford University Press/ Lane Contract, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence w/ Contributors (Correcting Spheres), 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Source Materials, When Women Ask The Questions, undated (Box 4, Folder 41654)
  - Mary Ann Irwin, Letters of Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Correspondence & Various Journals, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Body Images, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Catalysts and Messengers, 1998 July (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 3 Theory To Do, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ch TF Outline, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chapter 3 (TF) To Do, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dicsussion Disciplinary/Department, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Objectivity vs Scientific Objectivity, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Women Studies as a Discipline, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Critiques of Discipline, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Projects, 1990-1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Women in the Curriculum, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Feminism Research, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Women Studies vs Gender Studies E-mail Discussions, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ch. 4 To Do, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Feminism Pedagogy, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - The Personal Expense Assignment, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Misc. Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Feminist Pedagogy, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Feminist Pedagogy List, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Feminist Pedagogy Definitions, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Feminism Process, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Student Voices/Expeirence/Impact, 1986-1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Feminist Theory, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Womens Way of Knowing, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Chapter 4 Data, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Men, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Distance Learning & Women's Studies, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Chilly Climate for Women Faculty, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Intro, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Who is Others? Types & Discussions, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Afro-American, Whiteness, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Feminism Theory, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Coalition, 1994 Jun. 13 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Accusations, Denials, etc., 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Emboidment, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Collaboration Project/Women of Color & Multicultural Curriuculum, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Pedagogy, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Curriculium, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Bibliography Women of Color Studies, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Chapter 2 Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Chapter 3 Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Intro draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - G. Bowler, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Debate 3: Naming, 1994-2002 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Types of Feminism, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Feminism Essentialism, 1982 & 1995 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Poststrucalism & Postmodernism, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Scott Gender, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Experience, 1995 Jun. (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Science Q, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Theory For & Against, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Conclusion, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Table of Contents, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Engendering Modernity: Feminism, Social Theory, and Social Change, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Letters of Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Chapter 6: Academics/Advocacy Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Introduction, 1976 & 1989 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - References, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Various Notes & Readings, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Journals, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Letters of Correspondence, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Problems, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Activism - E-mail, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Conclusion, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Letters of Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Chapter 5 Draft 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Chapter 6 Theory, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Chapter 1 To Do, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Women Studies Abroad, 1994-2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Women Studies in United States, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Women Studies Survey of Students San Diego State University Falll 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - NWSA at Humboldt, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - National Women Studies Association Conference Notes, Flyers, etc, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - NWSA Conference Book, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - NWSA Notes, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women Studies Programs in Various Colleges, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NWSA, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NWSA, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NWSA, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ASU Women Studies Administration Confernece, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NWSA Albuquerque, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NWSA Statment and Scholarship, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - NWSA FFA, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Play Review, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Planning for Higher Education, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Liberal Education, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Situated Pedagogies: Classroom Practices in Postmodern Times, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Liberal Learning and the Arts of Connection for the New Academy, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - NWSAction, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - AAHE Bulletin, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Libreal Education, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Change, 1991 Nov. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Change, 1994 Oct. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - AACU Publications, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Feminist Studies Correspondents, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Addendem, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Women Studies Program Addresses, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondent Addresses, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Outline, Drafts, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Intro., undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Respect on Canon, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Trivial, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Political War Objection, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Multicultural P.C., undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Letters of Correspondence, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Paglia, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Magazines, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Patini, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sommus, 1991-1995 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - WFN, 1994-1998 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - WFN Conference, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Generations, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - The State of Women Studies, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - MJB Citation, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Not Academic Crit, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Conel, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Intro, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Context: History Gender, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Chapter 9: Outline and Drafts, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - The Post Post-Modern University, 1995 Apr. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Changing Academic Culture, 1985-1995 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - LEAD San Diego, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - The Cadre, 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Pedagogy Students, 1996-2002 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Public News, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Conclusion, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Chapter 8, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Chapter 9, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence WSPS, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Women Studies Program Admin Confference, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Santa Rosa, 1993 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-092
  - Notepad (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - M M stats (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spreadsheet (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SPSS notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SPSS notes (3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - UCC guide (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Occupations - male codes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - To Do (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Data set notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SPSSX (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2e (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 10e (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 11e (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Forms (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 18e (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 19e (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Copies MR brochures (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tilly, Louise (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tilly - Scott notes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tristan, Flua (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - U (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - V (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wollstonecraft (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wollstonecraft review (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Y (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Z (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - A (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SBA SB Anthony (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - BA - BL (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bo - Bu (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bebel (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bell/Offen vol. II (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Birth control (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Boxer - pubs (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - B/K Notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bridenthol (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bovary (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chafe (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - B/Q SW Quiggs and notes (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clancy - Smith (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - La Commune (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cott/Dlech (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - D (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Davidoff fam. Fortunes (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - N2 Davis (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Demography (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Addresses and archives (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Archives nationales - up (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1871 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1875 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1896 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1896 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1901 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Census, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1906 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1911 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ANFPLT, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1921 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1926 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Annuaire Statistepiu (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Apprentissage (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Artisan - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bibliographies (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Birthplaces (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bouvard S. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Budgets - Bourreu (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Bull de l'office du Travial, 1894 - 1907 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Coding (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Law of 1892 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Law 1892 application, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Law 1892 application, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Law 1892 application, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Law 1892 application, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Law of 1915 and enforcement (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Chamber de commerce (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Expo du Tad Bruxelles, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Congresses womens' except, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Contracts (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Contemporary (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Convents (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Couturieres (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Defenitions (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Diss CRs - P.L (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Enqueta - JM (notes) (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - the Empuete (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Eupuito - L (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Eupuito… roupe (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Eupueta - Claussures (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Eupuite - samedi (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Expositions (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Forms - blank (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Frequency distributions (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Health (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - History of flower making (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Iconology/Images (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Ideal (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - I D related articles (fiction) (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Dispectas AN notes (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - J. O. (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Like (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Literacy (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Manuals (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - MAPS - dept l (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Man. Rep form (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - 12e (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - 13e (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - 15e (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Migration (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Millinery (Modistes) (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous notes re paper (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Missing data etc. (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Non - French (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Notaries (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Occups - notes, articles (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Decs - feurale (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - F - M outline publisher's correspondence (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Perin (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - photos (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Process (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Prosti - Du Camp (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Rents (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Home, ind. Papers, recent (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Romance/ reality paper (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Abortion (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Abroad (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ads (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anthro (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Antis in media (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Autobiographies (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Awful stuff (bad examples) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Art (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Athletics (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cartoons (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Child care (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Climaj (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cohabitation (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Communes (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence SBVC (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Seminar (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Demography family - wills and stats (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Early modern biblio (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Educ - Q's, higher, US, stats (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous articles on higher education (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - G.E. humanities, NEH (Bennett) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Equal Ris amend (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - ERM (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Education profile women (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Fairytales (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Family FPA (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Family/marriage/ B. R. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Fascinating womanhood total Q and position Q (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Fashion (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Fear of women (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Feminology (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Generations/ life course (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Greeks (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Health (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - History studies (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Housework/domestic service (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Images "Ms" (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Impretions (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - International (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Jewish and Israeli (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Jewish mother stereotype (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Know inc. pubs (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Marriage and Mobility draft (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photocopies of articles related to marriage and mobility study (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - E (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Engels (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Elizabeth I (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Enlightenment (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - F (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Family - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fascism inc (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Flexner (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Freud on women (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Friedan (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - G (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gilligan: morality and Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Gilman (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Goldman Emma (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - H (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hause (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Helleistein et al victoria women (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Howe (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Howe (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Hutchisa (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Appleby (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - BA - BL (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Commane - Edwards (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bresards - Brandies (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Benoish (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bodue - Bouvier (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bouvier, J La Linpeire (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - BO (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - BR - BU (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - C (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Chevalieu L (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Commissions (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Geo Dupeux (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - E (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - F (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - France - Min. du Trav (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - G (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Guilbert, M (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - G (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Gemahling (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - H (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - I (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - J (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Kanipa (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - K (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - L (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Milhaud Carolin (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - N (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Noel (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - O (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Pic, Paul (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Perrot (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Q (Box 9, Folder 8)